A girl shouldn't have scars on her body.
Don't worry about me
I'll take care of myself
I burned everything
Nothing will lead to you anymore
Did you really kill everyone?
You're like an animal
You probably won't be forgiven
But I understand you
You are very unhappy... I think I understand you
She's mine
What did you just say?
This girl
belongs to me
I came to say that you seem to have made a mistake
Nothing here
doesn't belong to you
I promise you
No one will dare treat you like this again.
Don't say anymore that I "belong" to you
Then...
Should I call you "my man"?
I can't even control my feelings
No matter how hard I try to change my direction...
it doesn't work
Episode 5
Project coordinator and song translator: Nemie
Translators: Nemie, Kaia
Beta Editor: Sana
Typesetters: Nemie, Sana
Why here?
The princes' chambers are luxurious and clean
Why did you want to live here?
This is where I spend my time, this is my place!
This is the emperor's palace
Are you saying something here belongs to you?
That's not what I meant
Well that's good
Invading someone else's home is wrong
Is everything allowed for the prince? A?
You can't see the sky from my chambers
I can't look at the stars that rise only above Goryeo
Only over Koryo?
Is this possible?
Mung beans, mulberries, bletilla, buttercups!
Trichosanth roots, spikenard, galangal, bison, incense
Wow, look!
This was sent by the 8th Prince
Prince?
You were looking for something to do
He said you like medicinal herbs
But... what do you want to do with all this?
Soap for washing.
I'll make soap for you
I'm standing in front of you again, standing here alone
Tell me with your lips
Only "yes", only "yes"
I don’t understand why, but I always rush to you
With the wind blowing I will tell you: I love
Do you think the Queen will like these soaps, as your sister said?
Of course
There's not a person in Goryeo who doesn't like them
I'm standing in front of you again, standing here alone
Need to round up
Tell me with your lips
Only "yes", only "yes"
I don’t understand why, but I always rush to you
With the wind blowing I will tell you: I love
Need you!
My dear, so to speak I want
What I can’t say
My dear, my dear, my dear: I love you!
Looks funny
Let's do it again
I've never seen her so happy
She was inspired by the idea to make it for her mother-in-law
Maybe she didn't say
but she's sad because she lost her memory
However, she still remembers how it's done
This makes me happy
Su has become more mature after her injury
Often says wise things
but sometimes he acts his age, it's very cute
Many times I thought about sending her home
Now I'm glad I didn't do it
I want to find her a suitable match,
so that she can be with us for a long time
I want to see her smile
Yes
I feel the same
More...
I need to write a letter, can you provide me with a pen and ink?
Come to the library as soon as you finish your meal.
Sister, I'm here
Sister asked me to bring pen and ink
My wife's cough got worse, so she went to bed
She asked me to write this on her behalf
Oh yes...
Ink...
are lying here
Okay
This is Tao Yuanming's poem "Coming Home"
- You read it, right?
- Yes, yes... Yes...
When the lady writes a letter, she also writes a poem
What about you?
What?
Do you like poems or songs?
Poems... or songs?
Songs, of course
Really?
Unexpectedly
A noble lady loves common people's songs
What? Is he talking about the wrong songs?
Oh, he was talking about music in Koryo, stupid
No, no, I also love poetry more than songs
Then I'll give you this poem
I think I want to give it to you
Read it carefully
Thank you
- Chae Ryong!
- Yes, madam
Come here
This is what they gave me here
This...
I forgot how to read when I hit my head
What?
I'll learn again, but in the meantime, could you read this?
How do I know how to read?
I only know how to read my name
Sorry
Yang... Yang, Ryu, Chun, Chun, Kan, Su, Pyon!
I can only understand each hieroglyph individually,
but together it turns out to be bullshit
I'm illiterate, how can I live here?
His handwriting is as beautiful as he is
It would be great if I understood what was written
I want to read
I want to read, I want to read, I want to read
Why didn't I take Chinese lessons?
What are you doing?
- Lord
-Are you illiterate?
No
I can read
but I forgot everything when I hit my head
- Give it to me
- No, it's not worth it
Come on, I say!
Let's see
"The willows are green, the river water is calm,"
"I hear you, honey..."
You...
"The sun is peeking from the east, rain is coming from the west,"
"In words there is bad weather - and yet it is clear"
Beautiful poem
This is Liu Yuxi's poem "Bamboo Shoots"
Do you know its meaning?
"The willows are green, the river water is calm"
It's about a beautiful landscape, right?
It could not have been written by an illiterate person
Who gave it to you?
The 8th prince gave it for study
Is it true that you can't read?
Aren't you pretending?
No. Why would I pretend to be stupid?
The prince gave you a good poem, don't forget to thank him
Today you will have to greet the empress in the palace, get ready
In the palace? Will I go to the palace?!
Yes, you will give her the soap you made
Okay! Then I'll get ready!
Is my brother out of his mind?
This is an ordinary poem about a landscape
This is a poem about love
The last line implies “love”, this is a confession!
Are you telling me you don't know this?!
When you got married, I...
Really...
Did you already know everything?
Knew how Uk felt
Right?
Back A
Finish your drawing for me by the end of today
Sister...
This means the willow is green and the water is calm
Darling sings on the river
The sun is peeking out from the east...
And what is this?
No! No no
What other meaning could there be?
He's gone!
Stop thinking like that already
the prince is just... Yes, who is he?.. A landlord!
Think of it as a homeowner.
You need to control your heart
My heart, my
Homeowner, homeowner...
You have never come to Damiwon Palace
What brought you here?
Uk wanted to come with his wife and her cousin
My daughter-in-law is not well
I wanted to take some medicine from concubine O
I don't know why everyone trusts her so much
She is not a doctor, but a court lady
By the way, Prince Jeong has grown up a bit
I heard he has a private teacher?
The teacher is already approaching 70
He needs a teacher who will teach him not only life experience
Who taught Uka?
Uk picked up books every now and then
If something was unclear, I discussed it with the teacher
He abandoned his teacher early
Keep your teacher's name a secret?
Are you that worried about his little brother?
The 8th Prince has arrived
Greetings, your highnesses
Nice to meet you
Are you Hae Soo?
First time I see you up close
Of course very beautiful
Nice to meet you, Queen Hwangbo
This is my sister-in-law's sixth cousin
Yes...
Oh, it’s about you, apparently, Jeong told me
The girl who hit the 10th prince?
I've heard a lot about your deeds
They say you get along with my sons
Nice to meet you, Empress
Su gave you a gift
Oh my God! What a beauty
I've never seen anything like it
If you use it when washing your face,
your skin will become very... soft
Thank you, I will
We have prepared a gift for you too, Empress
And for me?
I know you are a fragrance connoisseur.
Accept it
You have a very good daughter-in-law, queen
It's a pity you don't have children
Then I would be perfect
They say great blessings don't come easy
Thanks for your concern
The Emperor has arrived!
This is Emperor Taejo, Wang Gon!
The founder of Koryo is Taejo!
I only saw him in dramas, but now I see him live
Holy shit
Have you arrived?
Looks like you had a nice conversation here
I heard that you are unwell
It seems that thanks to your care I will get better soon
Isn't this the girl who fought with Eun?
They were just playing
The game mutilated the prince's face
She's gone too far
How could this cute girl fight with Eun?
I deserve to die!
Are you afraid of the emperor?
Come to your senses
The tyrant lives on fear
and a wise ruler lives by virtue
You are a good and wise emperor, I am not afraid of you
Wise?
Why do you think I'm wise?
Do you want to get away from the topic with flattery?
Please, please, please, please!
Think, come up with something
Well...
You united three lands and founded a new country
You did not humiliate people from other lands, but appointed them to high positions
And more... more... what else?
Parhae, Parhae!
Parhe disappeared, but you remained faithful!
Therefore you are a wise ruler
She's very smart
My high school history teacher...
Sorry for cursing you when you asked me to remember this
Thank you, may the Lord bless you!
I guess you can do more than just fight
Reward her with a precious carpet
Yes, Your Majesty
Precious, Your Majesty?
What an honor for her!
Su, I need to thank you
Your generosity is limitless, Your Majesty!
Damn, where is the restroom?
I got nervous, my stomach hurts now
Where's the restroom?
Where? Where?
God
What are you doing here? This is no place for you
Became a completely different person
Now they will know that you are a prince
I was born him, a prince since childhood
What about you?
Came to spy on men?
I brought a gift to the Empress,
and the 8th prince allowed me to walk around the palace
Are you doing well here?
Of course
Like you said, this is my home, where my mother and brothers and sisters live.
Oh yes...
Too big for home
Do you go to see your parents every day?
I stayed here as I wanted.
Do you think you'll get what you want?
I sent you to that family as a gesture of goodwill.
And you didn't stay there
Useless
Born the same year, but you can’t hold a candle to Uku!
Your only skill is killing people
You don't know anything
How are you going to stay in the palace?
Thanks for your concern
I won't burden you
I use my only skill to avoid becoming a burden.
Is she really his mother?
Things are too terrible to witness.
Should I have told him I was leaving?
What has become more important than your health since you came?
Is there anyone here?!
Call a doctor immediately!
I need to tell you something
Child
You told me on your wedding day
They said I was the prince's source of strength
They said that you would fulfill one of my requests later.
Whatever it is, you promised that you would fulfill it
Child, what can I do for you?
Hae Soo...
Please accept her as the prince's wife
you know
I don't have many days left
Prince, have you come?
Chi Mon, I came to visit my mother
Uncle! You know me, right?
What?
We've met before
We... even drank together
What an outrageous story?
Soo, have you met astronomer Choi Chi Mon before?
Certainly!
Uncle, you really don’t know me?
I've been looking for you everywhere
But I don't know you, lady
I just recently found out that you are the cousin of the 8th Prince's wife
I didn't look like that back then
This was not in Goryeo
It was... like a thousand years in the future!
A thousand years later, in a park near a lake
Be careful
What?
Inside the palace
you must watch your every word
Various conversations in the palace can be dangerous
Especially conversations about the throne or the imperial family
If you have to stay here, you should know about the rules of life in the palace
Life cannot be changed by your own will
So you and Choi Chi Mon knew each other before?
I thought I knew him, but I was wrong
Okay
Wait
I made this for you when I made soap for the Empress and Queen.
I have a lot to thank you for
Oh, and thank you for the poem
Thank you
So do you know what the poem is about?
Of course
It's about a green willow that grows near the water.
And about a happy singing man
Wonderful poem
Then you should write back to me
What?
According to the rules of etiquette, one is supposed to respond verse to verse
Will you write me the one you like?
Yes
Wrong again!
White is paper. Black - letters on it
To quote something, I have to know it
I'll lose my mind so soon
How can I write an answer?
What to do now?
I shouldn't have pretended that I understood this.
I don't know!
Stop it! I'm serious!
Su!
What brings you here? Have you come to see me?
No really. I wanted to bring something
Is this food?
This is it?
Yes it is
I studied a poem with her and told her to write another one
- You can go
- Yes
Brother
Let's see what Hae Soo wrote
Wait
What is this? Did she write or draw this?
Idiots. Give it here
Brother, do you know what this is?
Well, that's...
But isn't this...
Are they written symbols or drawings?
You know?
Maybe you know, brother?
Raise your hands
To the sky
Open your mouth
Make it rounder
Yes. This is exactly what
Brother, this is funny
He's right. This is it
- Absolutely the same
- Let me see
You should watch everything!
This is the face that laughs in delight
Ah, a laughing face!
She probably really liked Uka's poem
And you try
And you are brother
Stop!
What are you doing?
What?
How can you do this to Myung Hee?
You know what kind of person she is
You know about her feelings for Wook. How can you do this?
What have I done that you scold me?
What have you done?
You keep exchanging glances with each other
When your hands accidentally touch,
you replay this moment in your head for a few more days
"What kind of food does he like?"
"What makes him laugh?"
This is probably all you think about!
Everything you look at makes you think of him.
These are the feelings that float between you!
Did you think no one would notice?
I know. And Myung Hee knows
Myung Hee knows everything
Does he know?
Listen carefully
All she has is Uk
She always looked only at him
If you... If you hurt her
I won't sit idly by
Sorry you had to hear that
It's my fault
I promised I wouldn't burden you
But it became your heaviest burden
It's not your fault, Su
It was I who gave you the poem
And I got yours
I wanted to make you laugh. It's all me
When I see you I
It's all my fault
I can’t breathe, I’m timid
Don't blame yourself. Please
It's as if everything in the world has stopped
I knew human feelings could be dangerous
If I pass by like a breeze,
I pretended not to notice and thought that everything would be resolved
you won't even notice
My heart is all given to you
I took your hand
And left my room that night
But loving you is very painful for me
It's my fault
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
Please
don't say that
so hard
Don't forget, please!
When I'm with you...
That eternal love of mine
I always cry
You burn with your gaze
As if you know everything yourself
Sorry
About what's on my heart
Even if I want to, I can’t leave
Holds the memories
Even when you and I are not around
But loving you is very painful for me
And so sad
I need to cross you out of my heart
so hard
Don't forget, please!
That eternal love...
mine
I thought it was time to change my pillow and did it for you
I will be the Emperor of Heaven when I sleep on such a decoration
My skills are still not perfect
They say fathers become fools around their daughters
That's exactly who I am
You are such a beautiful young girl. Who can I marry you to?
I am confident that you will make the right decision for me, Emperor
I want you to live happily, just like my eldest daughter
Unfortunately I rarely see her
Princess Naklan is now married and very happy, right?
Are you saying that you want to send me to live away from the palace?
And what? Don't you want to?
I will be happy in any place you choose for me
I will wait until you find me a worthy match, Emperor
Yong Hwa, how do you manage to always make me happy with your speeches?
You are the greatest joy for an old man
Thank you
Brother
Yes
Still not used to seeing you in the palace
And I still can’t get used to these clothes
Have you come to see the Emperor?
Yes
The Emperor plans to marry me off
Really? Has he already chosen someone?
The thing is...
What? You don't think it will be you, do you?
Don't cherish vain hopes
It's amazing that the emperor allowed you to stay and live in the palace
But he will never give his precious Yong Hwa to someone like you
Do you want to argue about it and see?
Only fools argue about such things
Let's ask Yong Hwa
Will she want to look at such an ugly face all her life?
I'm not looking for a handsome man
I need someone who will treasure me
Someone for whom I will be a treasure
He must know your worth in order to value you.
Yong Hwa, I would value you as an empress
You've always been so good to me brother
What about you, brother?
You're not asking me to evaluate you, are you?
I would prefer a woman with high self-esteem to someone who values me.
The one who won't be embarrassed by my ugly face
It's just words
He always acts like this
He's still just an animal
How fun must it be to transform an animal into a human?
Sometimes I'm very curious about it
Sister!
Sister, is everything okay?
Chae Ryong! Chae Ryong! Chae Ryong!
Is there anyone? Chae Ryong!
Su!
You
What are your feelings for the prince?
You're so stupid
You're both so stupid
You can
put makeup on me?
What?
For him
I want him to remember me as beautiful
Sister
Su
You can easily catch a cold
Always remember to drink honey and ginger
You live so close to the imperial family
Always be careful with your words and actions
I'm always worried about your temper
About the prince...
I want you to make a pillow for him
He has enough worries
I would like him to be comfortable in his sleep
I ask you...
take care of him
Prince! Prince!
- Su
- Sister
She's looking for you. Faster
Wife, I think we should go back inside.
I wanted to take a walk with you
I wanted us to admire the snow
Do you remember?
Remember when I first saw you?
I knew you thought that I would be a burden to you
And still insisted on the wedding
You were kicked out of the palace
You were the prince whose wings were clipped
I wanted to help you get up
wife
Why did you think I didn't know how you felt?
Now...
I want you, prince,
looked after Hae Soo
Think about my feelings for you
Please Su...
This child...
Wife? wife
wife
What you told me
I will never forget
You said
that I don't love you
Madam, I...
You...
don't have to say anything
But...
I was happy
love you more
That was enough
Sister
Don't wake her up from her sleep
Thanks for watching with us!
Release group MANIA
http://doramamania.mybb.ru
http://vk.com/doramamania
Scarlet Hearts: Ryeo
Another place and another time here, but I believe, you are my love
A fair wind will bring your scent, it’s so easy for me to recognize it
But I don't understand
When did you settle in my heart, tell me
I don't understand
Why is my heart beating fast?
You may suddenly pass by and not notice, have you forgotten me?